Guide to the North American Coalition for Christianity and Ecology Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
North American Coalition for Christianity and Ecology records
1986-2007
RG 225
Yale University Divinity School Library
9
(23 boxes)
These archives document the work of the North American Coalition for Christianity and Ecology, an ecumenical group that was formed in 1986 to highlight environmental dimensions of the Christian tradition, help Christian individuals and churches become more ecologically responsible, and work with people of other traditions in the common effort to create a more sustainable global society.
North American Coalition for Christianity and Ecology
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the North American Coalition for Christianity and Ecology, 2010
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
1985 Fr. Albert Fritsch of Appalachia Science in the Public Interest, David Haenke of the Ozarks Bioregional Project, and Fred Krueger of the San Francisco-based Eleventh Commandment Fellowship, decided to initiate a Christian Ecological movement in North America
1986 May An initial planning conference in Syria, Virginia was attended by forty people from various denominations.
1986 Incorporated as the North American Conference on Christianity and Ecology, a nonprofit organization
1987 Aug First conference held in Indiana was attended by more than 500 people.
1987, 1988 Offices were established in San Francisco and Washington, DC.
1987-1991 Following a successful conference in 1987, the organization almost immediately experienced power struggles, personality conflicts, and financial disputes between various factions on the Board of Directors. These controversies resulted in the resignations of a number of board members, a lawsuit by former board member John Freda for expenses incurred as secretary, and the founding of the North American Conference for Religion and Ecology by former executive co-director Don Conroy. Financial instability stalled the organization's rapid growth and closed the offices in San Francisco and Washington, DC. With the resignations of many of the first generation of Board members, an austerity budget, and the shift to an entirely volunteer staff, the organization recovered its footing.
1988-1991 Six regional NACCE conferences were held. In addition to holding regional Earth Day conferences and co-sponsoring Soil and Water Stewardship Week with the National Association of Conservation Districts, NACCE cosponsored an environmental seminar in Russia in 1991.
1989 Conference: "Survival of the Planet: A Challenge to Faith Communities" (Minneapolis, Minnesota)
1991 The NACCE journal, Firmament, was replaced by its newsletter, Earthkeeping News
1992 Established local groups in Illinois and North Carolina.
1993 Formed a Hospitality Network and Speakers Bureau, organized conferences in four different states, and co-sponsored the Parliament of World Religions in Chicago
1994 Sponsored collaborative projects and regional coalitions, such as the Christian Youth Ecology conference, which were cosponsored by the Presbyterian Church (USA) and the Ecumenical Ministries of of Southern California
1996 Conference: "Discerning the Signs of These Times" (Milwaukee, Wisconsin)
1996 Congress of Earthkeeping Ministries, which hosted "town meetings" on four trends affecting churches: eco-feminism, eco-justice, science and cosmology, and alternative economics. As a result of the conference, NACCE focused its efforts on sponsoring local eco-church circles to strengthen faith communities' care for creation.
1998 Changed its name to the North American Coalition for Christianity and Ecology, reflecting its shift from conferences to grassroots coalition-building and local eco-church circles
2001 Conference: "Spirit and Religion in the Ecological Age: Empowering Environmental Work" (Little Rock, Arkansas)
2004 Conference: "Bringing the Church Back Down to Earth," cosponsored by The Center for Progressive Christianity (St. Paul, Minnesota)
Scope and Contents
This collection thoroughly documents the development and operations of the North American Coalition for Christianity and Ecology and provides insight into the Christianity and ecology movement in the United States from 1986 to 2006. The mission statement of the NACCE indicates its areas of interest and activity: "The continuing devastation of Earth is a crisis of the human spirit. To address this crisis: 1)We will invite people into a loving relationship with Earth through the formation of local earthkeeping circles; 2) We will teach reverence for God's creation, with the understanding that humans are embedded in the natural world; 3) We will cooperate with other organizations concerned with ecology and social justice; 4) We will promote the study of ecological issues in the context of biblical theology and contemporary science."
Series I, Organization and Policy Records, contains legal documents related to the incorporation and name changes of NACCE, case files from Freda v. NACCE, by-laws, and other documents related to the founding and activities of the organization.
Series II, Board and Committee Records, contains minutes and other documents from the Board and Executive Committee meetings, lists of Board members from different periods, and correspondence pertaining to the recruiting and resignations of Board members.
Series III, Correspondence of Board Members, contains letters to and from individuals who were members of the Board of Directors.
Series IV, Programs and Conferences, documents programs, conferences, consultations, and workshops produced by NACCE.
Series V, Membership Records, includes membership lists, forms, and correspondence, as well as the organization's mailing lists.
Series VI, Publications and Publicity, contains NACCE's two serial publications, Firmament and Earthkeeping News, brochures, articles about the organization and its activities, audio and video tapes, photographs, and other documents.
Series VII, Financial Records, contains financial statements, ledgers, tax forms, grant proposals, and other records and correspondence by Board members pertaining to finances.
Series VIII, Collected Material, includes conference material and other documents from related organizations, resources from outside NACCE, and documents relating to individuals both within and outside of the organization.
Arrangement
I. Organization and Policy Records, 1986-2005
II. Board and Committee Records, 1986-1994
III. Correspondence of Board Members, 1986-2003
IV. Programs and Conferences, 1987-2006
V. Membership Records, 1989-2006
VI. Publications and Publicity, 1986-2006
VII. Financial Records, 1987-2006
VIII. Collected Material, 1987-2007
Environmentalism -- Religious aspects; North American Coalition for Christianity and Ecology
- Organization and Policy Records, 1986-2006; Series I
  - Legal documents, 1986-2003
    - Incorporation proceedings, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Legal correspondence, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Freda v. NACCE decision, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Freda v. NACCE correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Freda v. NACCE documents, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Freda v. NACCE - Fritsch, Al deposition, 1991 Jul (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Freda v. NACCE trial notebook, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Freda v. NACCE documents, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Freda v. NACCE proposed trial exhibits, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Freda v. NACCE witnesses and exhibits, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Freda v. NACCE case file, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Freda v. NACCE documents, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Freda v. NACCE index of pleadings, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Freda v. NACCE documents and exhibits, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Freda v. NACCE documents and exhibits, 1987-1991 (Box 3, Folder 15-18)
    - Freda v. NACCE billing statements, 1990-1993 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Russia pilgrimage: legal proceedings, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Name and registration changes, 1992-2003 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - By-laws, 1986-1994
    - By-laws, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - By-laws, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - By-laws, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Organizational records, 1987-2005
    - NACCE founding, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Organization histories, 1989-1999 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Committee structure, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Executive co-director job description and contracts, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Reports to Board of Directors and Executive Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Reports to Board of Directors, 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Krueger, Frederick contract - correspondence, 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Reorganization attempt, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Washington, D.C. office relocation and closing, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Team building, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Reports to members and friends of NACCE, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Organizational planning, 1992-2005 (Box 4, Folder 36-39)
    - Miscellaneous organizational records, 1988-2003 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Notice of dissolution of NAACE, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Board and Committee Records, 1986-2006; Series II
  - Meeting records, 1986-2006
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1986 Oct (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1987 May (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1987 Aug (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Board of Directors legal report and agenda, 1987 Oct (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1988 Feb (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1988 May (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Executive Committee metting, July 1988, 1988 Jul (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Board of Directors and Executive Committee meetings, 1988 Oct (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Executive Committee conference call, 1988 Dec (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Board of Directors and Executive Committee meetings, 1989 Jan (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Executive Committee meeting, 1989 Mar (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1989 May (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Executive Committee meeting, 1989 Jul (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1989 Sep (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Executive Committee conference call, 1989 Nov (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1990 Jan (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Board of Directors and Executive Committee meetings, 1990 May (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Board of Directors annual meeting, 1990 Oct (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Board of Directors quarterly meeting, 1991 Feb (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Board of Directors quarterly meeting, 1991 May (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Board of Directors annual meeting, 1991 Nov (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Board of Directors quarterly meeting, 1992 Jan (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Board of Directors quarterly meeting, 1992 Jun (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Board of Directors annual meeting, 1992 Oct (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Executive Committee meeting, 1992 Nov (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1993 Feb (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1993 Apr (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Board of Directors conference call, 1993 Jun (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Board of Directors annual meeting, 1993 Oct (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1994 Jan (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1994 Jun (Box 6, Folder 71)
    - Board of Directors conference call, 1994 Sep (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - Board of Directors teleconference, 1995 Feb (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Board of Directors meeting - teleconference, 1995 Jun (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Board of Directors and Conference Steering Committee meeting, 1995 Oct (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - Board of Directors meeting - teleconference, 1997 Jun (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1997 Nov (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - Board of Directors teleconference, 1998 Jun (Box 6, Folder 78)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1998 Nov (Box 6, Folder 79)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 2000 Jan (Box 6, Folder 80)
    - Board of Directors meeting - teleconference, 2000 May (Box 6, Folder 81)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 2000 Nov (Box 6, Folder 82)
    - Board of Directors conference call, 2001 Feb (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - Board of Directors annual meeting, 2001 Oct (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 2002 May (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - Board of Directors meeting - teleconference, 2002 Aug (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - Board of Directors working weekend, 2003 Oct (Box 6, Folder 87)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 2004 Jun (Box 6, Folder 88)
    - Board of Directors meeting - teleconference, 2004 Dec (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - Board of Directors teleconference, 2005 Aug (Box 6, Folder 90)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 2006 Nov (Box 6, Folder 91)
    - Board of Directors meeting notes, 2001-2005 (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - Membership of Board of Directors, 1988-1994
    - Members and nominees of the Board of Directors, 1988-1991 (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - Nominating Committee, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 94)
    - Resignations of Board members and executive co-directors, 1989-1994 (Box 6, Folder 95)
- Correspondence of Board Members, 1986-2003; Series III
  - Berry, James, 1988-1997 (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - Blewett, Jane, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - Bower, Susan, 1992-2002 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - Bryan, Jody, 1994-1999 (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - Conroy, Donald, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - DeWitt, Calvin, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - Dyson, Elizabeth, 1989-1993 (Box 7, Folder 102-105)
  - Dyson, Elizabeth for Earthkeeping News, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 106)
  - Dyson, Elizabeth, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 107)
  - Dyson, Elizabeth, 1995-2002 (Box 8, Folder 108-112)
  - Flitter, Michael, 1991-2003 (Box 8, Folder 113-114)
  - Freda, John, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 115-116)
  - Fritsch, Al, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 117-118)
  - Greene, Herman, 1995-1999 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - Hinkley, James, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - Holmes, Jenny, 1990-1998 (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - Krueger, Frederick, 1986-1993 (Box 9, Folder 122-124)
  - McAfee, Bob, 1996-1999 (Box 9, Folder 125)
  - Rae, Eleanor, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 126)
  - Schaef, Finley, 1993-2002 (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - Schutz, Robert, 1991-1993 (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - Testerman, Dennis, 1989-1999 (Box 10, Folder 129)
  - West, Melvin, 1992-1995 (Box 10, Folder 130)
  - Wilson-Youngchild, Gregory, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 131)
- Programs and Conferences, 1987-2006; Series IV
  - Programs and Workshops, 1989-2004
    - Regional workshops, 1989-1989 (Box 10, Folder 132)
    - Lifestyle workshop kit, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 133)
    - Earth Day, 1990 Apr (Box 10, Folder 134)
    - Washington Cathedral event/WWF, 1990 May (Box 10, Folder 135)
    - Russia pilgrimage, 1991 Aug (Box 10, Folder 136)
    - Regional contacts, hospitality network, speakers bureau, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 137)
    - Eco-church circles, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 138)
    - Eco-church circles, 1999-2000 (Box 11, Folder 139)
    - Eco-church circles, 2003-2004 (Box 11, Folder 140)
    - Bioregion workshop, 2003 Oct (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - Conferences and consultations, 1987-2006
    - North American Conference on Christianity and Ecology: proceedings, 1987 Aug (Box 11, Folder 142)
    - North American Conference on Christianity and Ecology: directory, 1987 Aug (Box 11, Folder 143)
    - North American Conference on Christianity and Ecology: planning and evaluation, 1987 Aug (Box 11, Folder 144)
    - North American Conference on Christianity and Ecology: articles, 1987 Aug (Box 11, Folder 145)
    - Renewing the Covenant: toward a Reformed theology on Justice, Peace, and the Integrity of Creation (JPIC), 1988 Oct (Box 11, Folder 146)
    - For the Transfiguration of Nature: a symposium on Holy Orthodoxy and the ecological crisis, 1989 Oct (Box 11, Folder 147)
    - Toward a New Church Order in Caring for Creation: planning, 1990 Oct (Box 11, Folder 148)
    - Toward a New Church Order in Caring for Creation: report, 1990 Oct (Box 11, Folder 149)
    - Sustaining Our Home, Planet Earth, 1993 Oct (Box 11, Folder 150)
    - Planting the Seeds youth conference, 1994 Sep (Box 11, Folder 151)
    - Congress of Earthkeeping Ministries: program and participants, 1996 Sep (Box 11, Folder 152)
    - Congress of Earthkeeping Ministries: ecofeminism town meeting, 1996 Sep (Box 11, Folder 153)
    - Congress of Earthkeeping Ministries: ecojustice town meeting, 1996 Sep (Box 11, Folder 154)
    - Congress of Earthkeeping Ministries: alternative economics town meeting, 1996 Sep (Box 11, Folder 155)
    - Congress of Earthkeeping Ministries: science and cosmology town meeting, 1996 Sep (Box 11, Folder 156)
    - Congress of Earthkeeping Ministries: report and debrief, 1996 Sep (Box 12, Folder 157)
    - Congress of Earthkeeping Ministries: planning, 1996 Sep (Box 12, Folder 158-160)
    - Congress of Earthkeeping Ministries: panelists, 1996 Sep (Box 12, Folder 161)
    - Congress of Earthkeeping Ministries: registration, 1996 Sep (Box 12, Folder 162)
    - Congress of Earthkeeping Ministries: finances, 1996 Sep (Box 12, Folder 163)
    - Congress of Earthkeeping Ministries: bills, 1996 Sep (Box 12, Folder 164)
    - Spirit and Religion in the Ecological Age, 2001 Oct (Box 12, Folder 165)
    - Bringing the Church Back Down to Earth: program and participants, 2004 Jun (Box 13, Folder 166)
    - Bringing the Church Back Down to Earth: planning, 2004 Jun (Box 13, Folder 167)
    - Legalizing the Rights of Earth and Community, 2006 Jul (Box 13, Folder 168-169)
- Membership Records, 1989-2006; Series V
  - Mailing lists, 1989-1992
    - Mailing lists, 1989-1992 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Membership forms, lists, and correspondence, 1990-2006
    - Membership lists, forms, and correspondence, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 171)
    - Membership forms and lists, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 172-173)
    - Membership forms, 1993-1995 (Box 14, Folder 174-178)
    - Membership forms, 1996-2001 (Box 15, Folder 179-184)
    - Membership forms, 2002-2006 (Box 16, Folder 185-189)
- Publications and Publicity, 1986-2006; Series VI
  - Serial publications, 1988-2006
    - Firmament, 1988-1993 (Box 16, Folder 190-191)
    - Firmament: correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 16, Folder 192)
    - Earthkeeping News, 1991-2006 (Box 16, Folder 193-197)
    - Earthkeeping News: planning, 1989-1991 (Box 16, Folder 198)
  - Other publications, 1986,-1990, n.d.
    - Brochures, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 199)
    - Art poster documents, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 200)
    - Christians for the Earth video: documents, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 201)
    - Where Are Our Churches Today? (survey), 1990 (Box 17, Folder 202)
  - Publicity, 1986-2000
    - Articles about NACCE and Christian ecology, 1988-1994 (Box 17, Folder 203)
    - Photographs, 1993-2000 (Box 17, Folder 204)
    - Audio cassettes (2): Lectures by Gene Marshall I. Spirit, Ecology & Christian Theology II. Fresh Wineskins for the Christian Breakthrough. From NACCE board meeting., 2000 Jan (Box 17)
    - Video cassettes (2, VHS): I. Science and New Cosmology; Christian Ecofeminism II. Ecojustice; Alternative Economics. From Congress of Earthkeeping Ministries., 1996 Sep (Box 17)
    - Video cassette (VHS): Christians for the Earth. Filmed at first NACCE conference., 1987 Aug (Box 17)
    - Video cassettes (2, VHS): I. Talks by John Cobb: Coming Down to Earth; Coming Down to Earth, Part 2. II. Talks by Sallie McFague: Taking Care of the Neighborhood: Some Reflections on Creation; A Call to Action. From Bringing the Church Back Down to Earth., 2004 Jun (Box 17)
    - Art poster, 1986 (Box OV-d4)
- Financial Records, 1987-2006; Series VII
  - Financial Statements, 1987-2006 (Box 18, Folder 205)
  - Auditor's report fiscal year 1988 and Board correspondence, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 206)
  - Auditor's report fiscal year 1991, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 207)
  - Ledger accounts and general journal, 1989-1992 (Box 18, Folder 208)
  - Ledger accounts, 1991-1998 (Box 18, Folder 209)
  - Ledger accounts and general journal, 1991-1993 (Box 18, Folder 210)
  - General journal, 1994-1998 (Box 18, Folder 211)
  - Ledger accounts, 1994-2004 (Box 18, Folder 212-213)
  - General journal and ledger, 2001-2005 (Box 18, Folder 214)
  - Spreadsheets, 1999-2006 (Box 18, Folder 215)
  - Program budgets, 1988-1992 (Box 18, Folder 216)
  - Tax-exempt status, 1987-1993 (Box 19, Folder 217)
  - IRS 990 tax forms, 1986-1996 (Box 19, Folder 218)
  - Washington D.C. and San Francisco office financial reports, 1988-1989 (Box 19, Folder 219)
  - Finance committee, 1988-1990 (Box 19, Folder 220)
  - Five year plan, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 221)
  - Business plan, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 222)
  - Fundraising letters to NACCE members, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 223)
  - Revolving loan fund, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 224)
  - Epiphany Press: correspondence, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 225)
  - San Francisco office inventory, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 226)
  - Video committee negotiations with Lou Niznik, 1988-1992 (Box 19, Folder 227)
  - Krueger, Frederick debt retirement and back taxes, 1993-1994 (Box 19, Folder 228)
  - Grant proposals and agencies, 1987-1992 (Box 19, Folder 229)
  - Finances: board correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 19, Folder 230-231)
  - Finances: board correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 20, Folder 232-233)
  - Miscellaneous financial records, 1987-1997 (Box 20, Folder 234)
- Collected Material, 1987-2007; Series VIII
  - Conferences of related organizations, 1987-2003
    - Building the Green Movement (sponsored by the Committees of Correspondence), 1987 Jul (Box 20, Folder 235)
    - People and the Earth, 1988 Apr (Box 20, Folder 236)
    - Seventh Assembly of the Fourth World, 1988 Jul (Box 20, Folder 237)
    - Survival of the Planet, 1989 Oct (Box 20, Folder 238)
    - Ninth Assembly of the Fourth World, 1990 Jul (Box 20, Folder 239)
    - North American Association for Environmental Education Conference, 1991 Sep (Box 20, Folder 240)
    - Earth Ethics Forum, 1991 Dec (Box 20, Folder 241)
    - Earth Stewardship 1992, 1992 Feb (Box 20, Folder 242)
    - Council for a Parliament of the World's Religions, 1993 Aug (Box 20, Folder 243)
    - Council for a Parliament of the World's Religions: program, 1993 Aug (Box 20, Folder 244)
    - Consultation on Ethical Relations with Other Creatures, 1993 Nov (Box 20, Folder 245)
    - Earth Stewardship 1994, 1994 Feb (Box 20, Folder 246)
    - Earth Stewardship 1995, 1995 Jan (Box 20, Folder 247)
    - Ethics, Economics, and Endangered Species, 1995 Oct (Box 20, Folder 248)
    - Renewing the Human Spirit (sponsored by Wisdom Ways), 1996 Jul (Box 20, Folder 249)
    - Faith and the Future, 1997 Apr (Box 21, Folder 250)
    - God's Earth: Our Home, 1997 May (Box 21, Folder 251)
    - Sisters of Earth, 1998 Jul (Box 21, Folder 252)
    - Forward in Faith (sponsored by Presbyterians Restoring Creation), 1998 Aug (Box 21, Folder 253)
    - The Biodiversity Project Spirituality Working Group, 1999 Mar (Box 21, Folder 254)
    - Council for a Parliament of the World's Religions, 1999 Dec (Box 21, Folder 255)
    - Making a Difference in Minnesota (sponsored by The Biodiversity Project), 2001 Mar (Box 21, Folder 256)
    - Earth Charter Community Summit 2001, 2001 Sep (Box 21, Folder 257)
    - The Symposium on Christian Resurgence for Century Twenty-One, 2002 Aug (Box 21, Folder 258)
    - Earth Charter Community Summit 2002, 2002 Sep (Box 21, Folder 259)
    - Earth Charter Community Summit 2003, 2003 Oct (Box 21, Folder 260)
  - Documentation from related organizations, 1989-2007
    - Center for Reflection on the Second Law, 1990-1993 (Box 21, Folder 261)
    - Community Environmental Legal Defense Fund, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 261a)
    - Eco-Justice Working Group, 1990-1993 (Box 21, Folder 262)
    - Environmental Sabbath, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 263)